	var quizArray = [{
		"id":"0",
		"question":"Nebular Hypothesis is a theory which is related to origin of the following?",
		"choice1":"a. Sun",
		"choice2":"b. Solar System",
		"choice3":"c. Galaxy",
		"choice4":"d. Universe",
		"correct":"b. Galaxy"
	},
	{
		"id":"1",
		"question":"Where is located the New Moore island",
		"choice1":"a. Arabian Sea",
		"choice2":"b. Indian Ocean",
		"choice3":"c. Bay of Bengal",
		"choice4":"d. Pacific Ocean",
		"correct":"c. Bay of Bengal"
	},
	{
		"id":"2",
		"question":"Open Sky Policy is related to which of the following?",
		"choice1":"a. Tourism",
		"choice2":"b. Aviation",
		"choice3":"c. Agriculture",
		"choice4":"d. Space Research",
		"correct":"b. Aviation"
	},
	{
		"id":"3",
		"question":"Oslo is capital of which of the following countries?",
		"choice1":"a. Denmark",
		"choice2":"b. Finland",
		"choice3":"c. Norway ",
		"choice4":"d. Sweden",
		"correct":"c. Norway"
	},
	{
		"id":"4",
		"question":"The winds which never change their direction are called?",
		"choice1":"a. Permanent Winds",
		"choice2":"b. Trade Winds",
		"choice3":"c. Planetary Winds",
		"choice4":"d. Local Winds",
		"correct":"c. Planetary Winds"
	},
	{
		"id":"5",
		"question":"In which of the following climates pine trees grow",
		"choice1":"a. Wet Deciduous",
		"choice2":"b. Coniferous",
		"choice3":"c. Tundra",
		"choice4":"d. Monsoon",
		"correct":"b. Coniferous"
	},
	{
		"id":"6",
		"question":"Rhodesia is the old name of ?",
		"choice1":"a. Zaire",
		"choice2":"b. Zimbabwe",
		"choice3":"c. Swaziland",
		"choice4":"d. Malawi",
		"correct":"b. Zimbabwe"
	},
	{
		"id":"7",
		"question":"In which of the following River Jordan drains?",
		"choice1":"a. Atlantic Ocean",
		"choice2":"b. Dead Sea",
		"choice3":"c. Swaziland",
		"choice4":"d. None of them",
		"correct":"b. Dead Sea"
	},
	{
		"id":"8",
		"question":"Which among the following was the first comet to be observed by a manned spacecraft?",
		"choice1":"a. Comet Kohoutek",
		"choice2":"b. Halley's Comet",
		"choice3":"c. Comet Borrelly",
		"choice4":"d. Kreutz Sungrazers",
		"correct":"a. Comet Kohoutek"
	},
	{
		"id":"9",
		"question":"The lines on a map connecting regions of equal rainfalls are called as which among the following?",
		"choice1":"a. Isobars",
		"choice2":"b. Isohyets",
		"choice3":"c. Isocons",
		"choice4":"d. Isotherms",
		"correct":"b. Isohyets"
	},
	{
		"id":"10",
		"question":"Littoral forests are rich sources of which among the following?",
		"choice1":"a. Bamboo",
		"choice2":"b. Firewood",
		"choice3":"c. Timber",
		"choice4":"d. Fodder",
		"correct":"b. Firewood"
	},
	{
		"id":"11",
		"question":"What are the main criteria of dividing major natural regions of the world?",
		"choice1":"a. Temperature, rain fall and vegetation",
		"choice2":"b. Latitudes and Longitudes",
		"choice3":"c. Atmospheric Pressure and Winds",
		"choice4":"d. All of them",
		"correct":"a. Temperature, rain fall and vegetation"
	},
	{
		"id":"12",
		"question":"Which among the following straits connects the Mediterranean Sea with Atlantic Ocean?",
		"choice1":"a. Strait of Gibraltar",
		"choice2":"b. Strait of Magellan",
		"choice3":"c. Strait of Panama",
		"choice4":"d. None of them",
		"correct":"a. Strait of Gibraltar"
	},
	{
		"id":"13",
		"question":"Moraines are the deposits of which among the following kinds?",
		"choice1":"a. Tidal deposits",
		"choice2":"b. Glacial Deposits",
		"choice3":"c. Wind Deposits",
		"choice4":"d. None of them",
		"correct":"b. Glacial Deposits"
	},
	{
		"id":"14",
		"question":"Where are the headquarters of International Union for Conservation of Nature and Natural Resources ?",
		"choice1":"a. Geneva",
		"choice2":"b. Philippines",
		"choice3":"c. Sydney",
		"choice4":"d. Sydney",
		"correct":"a. Geneva"
	},
	{
		"id":"15",
		"question":"Which among the following is the highest peak in Africa?",
		"choice1":"a. Mount Kilimanjaro",
		"choice2":"b. Mount Kenya",
		"choice3":"c. Mount Algan",
		"choice4":"d. Mount Hanang",
		"correct":"a. Mount Kilimanjaro"
	},
	{
		"id":"16",
		"question":"Which among the following migratory bird species migrates from Arctic to Antarctica every year, making it longest migratory route on earth?",
		"choice1":"a. Arctic Tern",
		"choice2":"b. Black necked swan",
		"choice3":"c. Bobolink",
		"choice4":"d. American Robin",
		"correct":"a. Arctic Tern"
	},
	{
		"id":"17",
		"question":"Which among the following seas is known for highest salinity?",
		"choice1":"a. Red Sea",
		"choice2":"b. Dead Sea",
		"choice3":"c. Caspian Sea",
		"choice4":"d. Sargasso Sea",
		"correct":"b. Dead Sea"
	},
	{
		"id":"18",
		"question":"What is normally found in the western side of the continents situated near tropics?",
		"choice1":"a. Mountains",
		"choice2":"b. Deserts",
		"choice3":"c. Rivers",
		"choice4":"d. Lakes",
		"correct":"b. Deserts"
	},
	{
		"id":"19",
		"question":"Approximately how much time does a Sun ray take reaching Earth?",
		"choice1":"a. 400 seconds",
		"choice2":"b. 500 seconds",
		"choice3":"c. 600 seconds",
		"choice4":"d. 700 Seconds",
		"correct":"b. 500 seconds"
	},
	{
		"id":"20",
		"question":"What is the number of known satellites of Jupiter?",
		"choice1":"a. 12",
		"choice2":"b. 14",
		"choice3":"c. 15",
		"choice4":"d. 21",
		"correct":"b. 14"
	},
	{
		"id":"21",
		"question":"How many times Sun is heavier than Earth?",
		"choice1":"a. 3,300 times",
		"choice2":"b. 33,000 times",
		"choice3":"c. 3,30,000 times",
		"choice4":"d. 33,30,000 times",
		"correct":"c. 3,30,000 times"
	},
	{
		"id":"22",
		"question":"How long does the Earth take to turn 1Â° Longitude during its rotation?",
		"choice1":"a. 4 minutes",
		"choice2":"b. 4 seconds",
		"choice3":"c. 4 hours",
		"choice4":"d. 40 Seconds",
		"correct":"a. 4 minutes"
	},
	{
		"id":"23",
		"question":"Which among the following dates would normally represent a Winter Solstice in Northern Hemisphere?",
		"choice1":"a. December 26",
		"choice2":"b. January 14",
		"choice3":"c. December 21",
		"choice4":"d. January 24",
		"correct":"c. December 21"
	},
	{
		"id":"24",
		"question":"Which among the following is the longest day in northern hemisphere?",
		"choice1":"a. June 21",
		"choice2":"b. March 21",
		"choice3":"c. September 21",
		"choice4":"d. May 31",
		"correct":"a. June 21"
	},
	{
		"id":"25",
		"question":"What kind of forests are found in Siberian climate?",
		"choice1":"a. Deciduous",
		"choice2":"b. Coniferous",
		"choice3":"c. Tropical",
		"choice4":"d. MontaneGrasslands",
		"correct":"b. Coniferous"
	},
	{
		"id":"26",
		"question":"Kip is a currency of which country?",
		"choice1":"a. Laos",
		"choice2":"b. Uganda",
		"choice3":"c. Cambodia",
		"choice4":"d. Brunei",
		"correct":"a. Laos"
	},
	{
		"id":"27",
		"question":"Sun is best kept in which among the following categories?",
		"choice1":"a. Red Dwarf ",
		"choice2":"b. Yellow Dwarf",
		"choice3":"c. Brown Dwarf",
		"choice4":"d. Helium white dwarf",
		"correct":"b. Yellow Dwarf"
	},
	{
		"id":"28",
		"question":"Prairies are the grasslands typically found in ?",
		"choice1":"a. North America",
		"choice2":"b. South America",
		"choice3":"c. Africa",
		"choice4":"d. Australia",
		"correct":"a. North America"
	},
	{
		"id":"29",
		"question":"What is 2005 YU55 , which recently came close to earth?",
		"choice1":"a. An Asteroid",
		"choice2":"b. A Comet",
		"choice3":"c. A Meteoroid",
		"choice4":"d. None of them",
		"correct":"a. An Asteroid"
	},
	{
		"id":"30",
		"question":"What is the name of Earth's first super continent?",
		"choice1":"a. Pangea",
		"choice2":"b. Vaalbara",
		"choice3":"c. Gondwana",
		"choice4":"d. Columbia",
		"correct":"b. Vaalbara"
	},
	{
		"id":"31",
		"question":"Which volcano is called the light pillar of Mediterranean sea?",
		"choice1":"a. Mount Barbaro",
		"choice2":"b. Stromboli",
		"choice3":"c. Mounth Etna",
		"choice4":"d. Mount Vesuvius",
		"correct":"b. Stromboli"
	},
	{
		"id":"32",
		"question":"In which country is located World's largest trade centre of diamond?",
		"choice1":"a. Belgium",
		"choice2":"b. India",
		"choice3":"c. USA",
		"choice4":"d. France",
		"correct":"a. Belgium"
	},
	{
		"id":"33",
		"question":"Lloyd Barrage is a 6166 mile long network of canals, feeding the largest irrigation system in the world, with more than 5 million acres of irrigated land. In which country it is located?",
		"choice1":"a. China",
		"choice2":"b. Pakistan",
		"choice3":"c. India",
		"choice4":"d. Afghanistan",
		"correct":"b. Pakistan"
	},
	{
		"id":"34",
		"question":"In which among the following countries is located the Owen Falls' that is world's greatest man made lake?",
		"choice1":"a. Uganda",
		"choice2":"b. Rwanda",
		"choice3":"c. Tanzania",
		"choice4":"d. Congo",
		"correct":"a. Uganda"
	},
	{
		"id":"35",
		"question":"Which among the following country is using the Nine-dotted line theory to claim a territory in South China Sea ?  ",
		"choice1":"a. China",
		"choice2":"b. Philippines",
		"choice3":"c. Vietnam",
		"choice4":"d. Cambodia",
		"correct":"a. China"
	},
	{
		"id":"36",
		"question":"Isohaline are the lines joining the points in the ocean that have equal _____?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Density",
		"choice2":"b. Salinity ",
		"choice3":"c. Temperature",
		"choice4":"d. None of them",
		"correct":"b. Salinity"
	},
	{
		"id":"37",
		"question":"Which among the following region is called as rust belt of Japan?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Shikoku",
		"choice2":"b. Honshu",
		"choice3":"c. Kyush",
		"choice4":"d. Chubu",
		"correct":"a. Shikoku"
	},
	{
		"id":"38",
		"question":"The Ghoramara Island, which was making news due to its submersion because of erosion and sea level rise is located in which among the following?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Arabian Sea",
		"choice2":"b. Bay of Bengal",
		"choice3":"c. Indian Ocean",
		"choice4":"d. Pacific Ocean",
		"correct":"b. Bay of Bengal"
	},
	{
		"id":"39",
		"question":"Mogao Caves, also known as 'Caves of the Thousand Buddhas' are located in which among the following countries?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Cambodia",
		"choice2":"b. China",
		"choice3":"c. Japan",
		"choice4":"d. Vietnam",
		"correct":"b. China"
	},
	{
		"id":"40",
		"question":"In which state is located the Shahgarh landscape, which has been chosen as the abode for reintroduction of Cheetah?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Gujarat",
		"choice2":"b. Madhya Pradesh",
		"choice3":"c. Rajasthan",
		"choice4":"d. Uttar Pradesh",
		"correct":"c. Rajasthan"
	},
	{
		"id":"41",
		"question":"On which among the following dates Earth may be on Perihelion (Closest to Sun)?  ",
		"choice1":"a. January 4",
		"choice2":"b. June 21",
		"choice3":"c. March 22",
		"choice4":"d. December 21",
		"correct":"a. January 4"
	},
	{
		"id":"42",
		"question":"What is the amount in percentage of total mass , which Sun comprises of the solar system  ",
		"choice1":"a. 90.02%",
		"choice2":"b. 93.24%",
		"choice3":"c. 98.20%",
		"choice4":"d. 99.8%",
		"correct":"d. 99.8%"
	},
	{
		"id":"43",
		"question":"What is the amount of Iron in Earth percentage in total mass?  ",
		"choice1":"a. 24.5%",
		"choice2":"b. 34.6%",
		"choice3":"c. 39.3%",
		"choice4":"d. 42.4%",
		"correct":"b. 34.6%"
	},
	{
		"id":"44",
		"question":"Phobes and Deimos are two satellites of which planet?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Jupiter",
		"choice2":"b. Mars",
		"choice3":"c. Saturn",
		"choice4":"d. Venus",
		"correct":"b. Mars"
	},
	{
		"id":"45",
		"question":"Who was the first to observe Saturn with a telescope?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Galileo Galilei",
		"choice2":"b. Issac Newton",
		"choice3":"c. Jacques Cassini",
		"choice4":"d. David H. Levy",
		"correct":"a. Galileo Galilei"
	},
	{
		"id":"46",
		"question":"Which planet is known as  Bright Wandering Star ?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Mars",
		"choice2":"b. Venus",
		"choice3":"c. Jupiter",
		"choice4":"d. Saturn",
		"correct":"c. Jupiter"
	},
	{
		"id":"47",
		"question":"Which among the following starts represent the Morning and Evening Stars?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Mercury, Venus",
		"choice2":"b. Venus, Mercury",
		"choice3":"c. Venus, Venus",
		"choice4":"d. Mercury, Mercury",
		"correct":"c. Venus, Venus"
	},
	{
		"id":"48",
		"question":"The time required by earth in 360 degree rotation to make a star return to the same position is called â¦â¦â¦â¦day?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Solar Day",
		"choice2":"b. Sidereal Day",
		"choice3":"c. Real Day",
		"choice4":"d. Synodic day",
		"correct":"b. Sidereal Day"
	},
	{
		"id":"49",
		"question":"On Summer Solstice, Sun's rays fall perpendicular on which among the following circles?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Tropic of Capricorn",
		"choice2":"b. Equator",
		"choice3":"c. Tropic of Cancer",
		"choice4":"d. None of them",
		"correct":"c. Tropic of Cancer"
	},
	{
		"id":"50",
		"question":"Which elements are found mostly in Lithosphere?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Aluminium & Silicon",
		"choice2":"b. Aluminium & Iron",
		"choice3":"c. Magnesium and Silicon",
		"choice4":"d. Silicon & Iron",
		"correct":"a. Aluminium & Silicon"
	},
	{
		"id":"51",
		"question":"Mars appears red because of presence of the following compounds on its surface?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Copper Oxide",
		"choice2":"b. Iron Oxide",
		"choice3":"c. Copper Sulphide",
		"choice4":"d. Magnesium Oxide",
		"correct":"b. Iron Oxide"
	},
	{
		"id":"52",
		"question":"Which among the following molecule is rarely found in universe but abundant on earth?  ",
		"choice1":"a. CO2",
		"choice2":"b. O2",
		"choice3":"c. CH4",
		"choice4":"d. He",
		"correct":"b. O2"
	},
	{
		"id":"53",
		"question":"Anatolia is a part of which among the following ?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Australia",
		"choice2":"b. Asia",
		"choice3":"c. North America",
		"choice4":"d. Antarctica",
		"correct":"b. Asia"
	},
	{
		"id":"54",
		"question":"In which among the following states of United States, Death Valley is located?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Miami",
		"choice2":"b. Pennsylvania",
		"choice3":"c. Texas",
		"choice4":"d. California",
		"correct":"d. California"
	},
	{
		"id":"55",
		"question":"What is the number of Galilean moons of Jupiter discovered by Galileo Galilei in January 1610?  ",
		"choice1":"a. 2",
		"choice2":"b. 3",
		"choice3":"c. 4",
		"choice4":"d. 5",
		"correct":"c. 4"
	},
	{
		"id":"56",
		"question":"Which among the following country is known as Land of White Elephant?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Thailand",
		"choice2":"b. Myanmar",
		"choice3":"c. Indonesia",
		"choice4":"d. Sri Lanka",
		"correct":"a. Thailand"
	},
	{
		"id":"57",
		"question":"Chaukhtatgyi Pagoda, which is home to statue of largest reclining Buddha in the world is located in which of the following countries or regions?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Thailand",
		"choice2":"b. Myanmar",
		"choice3":"c. India",
		"choice4":"d. Tibet",
		"correct":"b. Myanmar"
	},
	{
		"id":"58",
		"question":"Which among the following countries is known as Land of Thousand Lakes?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Norway",
		"choice2":"b. Finland",
		"choice3":"c. Sweden",
		"choice4":"d. Estonia",
		"correct":"b. Finland"
	},
	{
		"id":"59",
		"question":"Which among the following types of mountains are formed by the lifting up of land between faults or by the sinking of land outside the faults?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Block Mountains",
		"choice2":"b. New Mountains",
		"choice3":"c. Residual Mountains",
		"choice4":"d. Fold Mountains",
		"correct":"a. Block Mountains"
	},
	{
		"id":"60",
		"question":"Northern hemisphere is considered as more suitable for deep-space observation. Which among the following is a correct reason for this?  ",
		"choice1":"a. North Pole faces galactic centre of the Milky Way",
		"choice2":"b. North Pole faces away from galactic centre of the Milky Way",
		"choice3":"c. North Pole is farthest from Sun all around a year",
		"choice4":"d. Earth is inclined 1.57869Â° to Invariable plane",
		"correct":"b. North Pole faces away from galactic centre of the Milky Way"
	},
	{
		"id":"61",
		"question":"Who among the following is known as the first to measure the distance round the earth and also known as Father of Geometry?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Eratosthenes",
		"choice2":"b. Euclid",
		"choice3":"c. Happarchus",
		"choice4":"d. Galileo",
		"correct":"b. Euclid"
	},
	{
		"id":"62",
		"question":"Which among the following comes under the study area of Psychrometrics?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Relative Humidity",
		"choice2":"b. physical and thermodynamic properties of gas-vapor mixtures",
		"choice3":"c. theory and technique of educational and psychological measurement",
		"choice4":"d. Atmospheric Pressure at Colder Regions of the World",
		"correct":"b. physical and thermodynamic properties of gas-vapor mixtures"
	},
	{
		"id":"63",
		"question":"In which country is located world's largest Geothermal Power Plant?  ",
		"choice1":"a. United States",
		"choice2":"b. Canada",
		"choice3":"c. Kenya",
		"choice4":"d. Philippines",
		"correct":"a. United States"
	},
	{
		"id":"64",
		"question":"In which of the deserts is located the Death Valley   ",
		"choice1":"a. Mojave Desert",
		"choice2":"b. Colorado Desert",
		"choice3":"c. Amargosa Desert",
		"choice4":"d. Taklamakan Desert",
		"correct":"a. Mojave Desert"
	},
	{
		"id":"65",
		"question":"Ganymede which is the largest natural satellite in the Solar System is a satellite of ______?   ",
		"choice1":"a. Jupiter",
		"choice2":"b. Saturn",
		"choice3":"c. Uranus",
		"choice4":"d. Neptune",
		"correct":"a. Jupiter"
	},
	{
		"id":"66",
		"question":"Which among the following is an organic mineral?   ",
		"choice1":"a. Amber",
		"choice2":"b. Hornblende",
		"choice3":"c. Angite",
		"choice4":"d. Analcime",
		"correct":"a. Amber"
	},
	{
		"id":"67",
		"question":"Which among the following is true regarding cyclones?  ",
		"choice1":"a. rotate counter clockwise in the Northern Hemisphere and clockwise in the Southern Hemisphere",
		"choice2":"b. rotate clockwise in the Northern Hemisphere and counter clockwise in the Southern Hemisphere",
		"choice3":"c. may rotate in any direction in any hemisphere",
		"choice4":"d. None of them",
		"correct":"a. rotate counter clockwise in the Northern Hemisphere and clockwise in the Southern Hemisphere"
	},
	{
		"id":"68",
		"question":"Which among the following phenomena has been largely responsible for the recent drought in Somalia and northern Kenya?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Nino Southern Oscillation",
		"choice2":"b. La Nina",
		"choice3":"c. Indian Ocean Dipole",
		"choice4":"d. A collective impact of all the above three",
		"correct":"b. La Nina"
	},
	{
		"id":"69",
		"question":"Recently, it has been discovered that Earth is not alone in its orbit around the Sun. There is a small Trojan asteroid 2010TK7. Why this Trojan Asteroid does not collide with the earth ?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Because the asteroid and earth are constantly on the same orbit",
		"choice2":"b. Because the asteroid and earth are on different orbits",
		"choice3":"c. Because Trojan Asteroid revolve around the earth like satellite",
		"choice4":"d. None of the above reason",
		"correct":"a. Because the asteroid and earth are constantly on the same orbit"
	},
	{
		"id":"70",
		"question":"If place X and Place Y, both located on equator, are at a distance of 18520 kilometers, the approximate difference between their longitudes will be ____?   ",
		"choice1":"70 a. 100Â°",
		"choice2":"70 b. 120Â°",
		"choice3":"70 c. 166Â°",
		"choice4":"70 d. 180Â°",
		"correct":"70 c. 166Â°"
	},
	{
		"id":"71",
		"question":"The pointer or arrow of the magnetized needle of a compass indicates which among the following?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Geographic North Pole",
		"choice2":"b. Magnetic North Pole",
		"choice3":"c. Geo-magnetic North Pole",
		"choice4":"d. Magnetic South Pole",
		"correct":"d. Magnetic South Pole"
	},
	{
		"id":"72",
		"question":"Which among the following is the lowest level of a body of water such as an ocean or a lake?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Neritic",
		"choice2":"b. Pelagic",
		"choice3":"c. Benthic",
		"choice4":"d. Demersal",
		"correct":"c. Benthic"
	},
	{
		"id":"73",
		"question":"Which among the following methods of heat transfer is maximum responsible for heating of the lower layers of the atmosphere near earth's surface?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Radiation from Sun",
		"choice2":"b. Radiation from Earth",
		"choice3":"c. Conduction",
		"choice4":"d. Convection",
		"correct":"b. Radiation from Earth"
	},
	{
		"id":"74",
		"question":"Where on the earth is located the Sirohi Point?   ",
		"choice1":"a. North Pole",
		"choice2":"b. Indian Ocean",
		"choice3":"c. Caribbean Sea",
		"choice4":"d. Antarctica",
		"correct":"b. Indian Ocean"
	},
	{
		"id":"75",
		"question":"Which among the following is formed by the process of Lithification?   ",
		"choice1":"a. Granite",
		"choice2":"b. Basalt",
		"choice3":"c. Feldspar",
		"choice4":"d. Marble",
		"correct":"c. Feldspar"
	},
	{
		"id":"76",
		"question":"Which among the following natural satellites of our solar system is smaller than Moon?   ",
		"choice1":"a. Callisto ",
		"choice2":"b. Titan",
		"choice3":"c. Lo",
		"choice4":"d. Europa",
		"correct":"d. Europa"
	},
	{
		"id":"77",
		"question":"Which among the following soil is predominantly found in Rarh Region of West Bengal   ",
		"choice1":"a. Alluvial Soil",
		"choice2":"b. Red Soil",
		"choice3":"c. Black Soil",
		"choice4":"d. Acid sulfate soil",
		"correct":"b. Red Soil"
	},
	{
		"id":"78",
		"question":"Which among the following is the correct location of Earth's magnetosphere?   ",
		"choice1":"a. Near the centre of Earth",
		"choice2":"b. Below Ionosphere",
		"choice3":"c. Beyond Ionospher",
		"choice4":"d. Within 12-16 kms of Earth's surface",
		"correct":"c. Beyond Ionosphere"
	},
	{
		"id":"79",
		"question":"The unit less measure of Earth's reflectivity which is combined effect of all shortwave losses is known as ___?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Earth Scattering",
		"choice2":"b. Earth Radiation",
		"choice3":"c. Earth Albedo",
		"choice4":"d. Polar See-saw",
		"correct":"c. Earth Albedo"
	},
	{
		"id":"80",
		"question":"Which among the following is the tide of minimum rise?   ",
		"choice1":"a. Spring Tide",
		"choice2":"b. Low Tide",
		"choice3":"c. Ebb Tide",
		"choice4":"d. None of them",
		"correct":"b. Low Tide"
	},
	{
		"id":"81",
		"question":"Which among the following is the correct term for the inner portion of moon's shadow?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Umbra",
		"choice2":"b. Penumbra",
		"choice3":"c. Antumbra",
		"choice4":"d. Adularescence",
		"correct":"a. Umbra"
	},
	{
		"id":"83",
		"question":"Which of the following countries is not a part of far East?   ",
		"choice1":"a. Myanmar",
		"choice2":"b. Taiwan",
		"choice3":"c. China",
		"choice4":"d. Philippines",
		"correct":"a. Myanmar"
	},
	{
		"id":"84",
		"question":"Nickel & Iron are the main constituents of __________?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Earth Core",
		"choice2":"b. Earth Crust",
		"choice3":"c. Mantle",
		"choice4":"d. None of them",
		"correct":"a. Earth Core"
	},
	{
		"id":"85",
		"question":"Lithosphere includes the crust and the uppermost mantle, which constitute the hard and rigid outer layer of the planet in the range of 0 to _______?  ",
		"choice1":"a. 20 kms",
		"choice2":"b. 200 kms",
		"choice3":"c. 800 kms",
		"choice4":"d. 500 kms",
		"correct":"b. 200 kms"
	},
	{
		"id":"86",
		"question":"Which among the following country has the same time as of New Delhi   ",
		"choice1":"a. Kathmandu",
		"choice2":"b. Dhaka",
		"choice3":"c. Colombo",
		"choice4":"d. Spain",
		"correct":"c. Colombo"
	},
	{
		"id":"87",
		"question":"Which among the following has highest velocity ?   ",
		"choice1":"a. Hurricane",
		"choice2":"b. Tornado",
		"choice3":"c. Typhoon",
		"choice4":"d. Tropical Depression",
		"correct":"b. Tornado"
	},
	{
		"id":"88",
		"question":"Waterspout is a ___________?   ",
		"choice1":"a. Depression",
		"choice2":"b. Hurricane",
		"choice3":"c. Tornado",
		"choice4":"d. Typhoon",
		"correct":"c. Tornado"
	},
	{
		"id":"89",
		"question":"An eye of a cyclone is a central circular region characterized by which of the following?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Towering thunderstorms",
		"choice2":"b. Light winds and clear skies",
		"choice3":"c. Most severe weather of a cyclone",
		"choice4":"d. Winds with Highest Velocity",
		"correct":"b. Light winds and clear skies"
	},
	{
		"id":"90",
		"question":"Which among the following is the most abundant element by mass in Earth's Crust ?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Iron",
		"choice2":"b. Aluminum",
		"choice3":"c. Nickel",
		"choice4":"d. Oxygen",
		"correct":"d. Oxygen"
	},
	{
		"id":"91",
		"question":"As per the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea , what is the territorial limit of littoral states for exploitation of Oil and Gas in the seas?  ",
		"choice1":"a. 200 Miles",
		"choice2":"b. 350 Miles",
		"choice3":"c. 300 miles",
		"choice4":"d. 400 Miles",
		"correct":"b. 350 Miles"
	},
	{
		"id":"92",
		"question":"How many main Tropical cyclone warning centers are there in the world?  ",
		"choice1":"a. 5",
		"choice2":"b. 6",
		"choice3":"c. 10",
		"choice4":"d. 15",
		"correct":"b. 6"
	},
	{
		"id":"93",
		"question":"Near which of the following countries a Tropical Storm will originate?  ",
		"choice1":"a. England",
		"choice2":"b. West Indies",
		"choice3":"c. China",
		"choice4":"d. Norway",
		"correct":"b. West Indies"
	},
	{
		"id":"94",
		"question":"What is the name of the mountain range in central Asia, where Russia, China, Mongolia and Kazakhstan come together?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Altai Mountains",
		"choice2":"b. Sayan Mountains",
		"choice3":"c. Ural Mountains",
		"choice4":"d. Baikal Mountains",
		"correct":"a. Altai Mountains"
	},
	{
		"id":"95",
		"question":"What does an Epicentre of an earthquake means ",
		"choice1":"a. point of initial rupture",
		"choice2":"b. point at ground level directly above the point of initial rupture",
		"choice3":"c. Circle of earthquake disturbances",
		"choice4":"d. None of the above",
		"correct":"b. point at ground level directly above the point of initial rupture"
	},
	{
		"id":"96",
		"question":"In which of the following oceans world's largest island is located?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Atlantic",
		"choice2":"b. Arctic",
		"choice3":"c. Pacific",
		"choice4":"d. Indian",
		"correct":"b. Arctic"
	},
	{
		"id":"97",
		"question":"What is the difference of time on either side of the International Time Line?   ",
		"choice1":"a. 0 Hours",
		"choice2":"b. 12 hours",
		"choice3":"c. 24 Hours",
		"choice4":"d. 48 Hours",
		"correct":"c. 24 Hours"
	},
	{
		"id":"98",
		"question":"Pastoral Farming is usually related to ________?  ",
		"choice1":"a. Cereal Crops",
		"choice2":"b. Grazing for livestock",
		"choice3":"c. Integrated farming",
		"choice4":"d. None of them",
		"correct":"b. Grazing for livestock"
	},
	{
		"id":"99",
		"question":"Astronomical unit (AU) is a unit of length equal to about ?  ",
		"choice1":"a. 100 Million Kms",
		"choice2":"b. 150 Million Kms",
		"choice3":"c. 100 Billion Kms",
		"choice4":"d. 150 billion Kms",
		"correct":"b. 150 Million Kms"
	}
	];